# **VICTOR TRIPODI**

LI: Linkedin/victor-tripodi

M: 0423 435 792

E: vtripodi1989@gmail.com

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

I am an ambitious and proactive Accountant with a successful track record in providing strong financial and business support in challenging, high-pressure environments. With advanced analytical and technical skills, I deliver high quality, evidence-based insights and expert advice to help shape strategic direction and drive business outcomes. Detail and results-focused, I specialise in providing process and system improvements, cost-saving initiatives and accounting best practice, to create the optimum financial framework for commercial success. My significant communication and inter-personal capabilities allow me to build productive relationships with stakeholders at all levels and provide outstanding business partnership organisation-wide.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

✓ Accounting Expertise

✓ Business Partnership

✓ Analytical Skills

√ Stakeholder Relationships

√ Communication Skills

√ Eager to learn

√ Forecasting & Budgeting

√ Financial Modelling

√ Technological Aptitude

√ Team Leadership

√ Commercial Focus

√ System & Process Improvements

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

POSITION	ORGANISATION	DATES
Assistant Accountant	BCD Travel	Jan 2022 – Sep 2022
Assistant Accountant	La La Land	Nov 2020 – Dec 2021
Senior Financial Accountant	Agrocentro, PGG Wrightson	Jul 2017 to Feb 2020
Financial Accountant	Agrocentro, PGG Wrightson	Aug 2014 to Jun 2017
Assistant Accountant	Bado, Kuster, Zerbino & Rachetti	Jun 2013 to Jul 2014
Assistant Accountant	Bianchi & Associates	Apr 2011 to May 2013



#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Assistant Accountant, BCD Travel – Sydney, Australia

Jan 2022 – Sep 2022

#### Responsibilities

- Critical role in the month-end closure procedures, preparing and posting journals, BS reconciliations, P/L variance analysis
- Prepare and maintain monthly reconciliations, resolving discrepancies and collaborating across functions
- Business partner with several internal stakeholders, such as Sales, Operations and Human Resources
- Manage capital expenditure maintenance for all fixed assets
- Assist throughout the half-year and year-end audit processes through providing necessary support, answering queries, and assisting with financial statement preparation.
- Preparing weekly cash reporting and assisting in cash flow forecasting.
- Leading quarterly forecasting process (operating expenses).

#### Assistant Accountant, La La Land – Sydney, Australia

Nov 2020 - Dec 2021

La Land grew from the humble beginnings of a garage office to, a decade later, become one of Australia's most loved, leading giftware and homeware brand. The talented in-house design team creates and illustrates an incredible array of forward-thinking, trend sitting works, including the today, fiercely followed Australiana print.

#### **Responsibilities**

- Manage the monthly general ledger reconciliation process, including the processing of transactions and journals with responsibility for maintaining the integrity of key balance sheet accounts.
- Provide reliable and timely reporting and analytical support to our Commercial Finance Manager. This involves compiling, interpreting and reporting of financial information.
- Working closely with operations teams to support key analyses of volume, sales, expense control and other
  ad hoc reviews, in addition to collaborating on key improvement initiatives to support the growth of the
  company.
- Responsible for all accounts payable and accounts receivable tasks

#### Senior Financial Accountant, Agrocentro – PGG Wrightson, Uruguay

Jul 2017 - Feb 2020

Agrocentro is an agribusiness retailer selling seeds, fertilizers, agrochemicals, veterinary goods, and animal nutrition products through several branches around Uruguay. In 2015 it became part of New Zealand-based PGG Wrightson. My role was group-focused with reporting responsibilities to New Zealand.

#### **Responsibilities**

- Prepare accurate, detailed and timely monthly P&L and balance sheet reporting in line with New Zealand head office deadlines.
- Work closely with the CFO and CEO to establish a robust financial framework which mitigates risk, facilitates growth, and supports the business to deliver strongly against targets.

## VICTOR IRIPODI

- Contribute to the annual business planning and budgetary processes, constructing accurate and relevant forecasts and building detailed budgets through comprehensive financial analysis.
- Consolidate financial statements across all branches and producing weekly reports with analysis of accounts receivable and accounts payable.
- Present results and variance analysis to the commercial team, advising on fiscal performance against budgets and forecasts, highlighting risk and promoting informed decision-making.
- Proactively identify and support business improvement and enhancement initiatives through financial modelling and technical advice.
- Lead the treasury department, building and managing productive relationships with suppliers to improve terms and prices.
- Manage and mentor a team of eight staff, providing constant supervision and guidance as well as training on specific accounting competencies and professional development.

#### **Achievements**

- Successfully integrated the treasury processes into my team without the need for additional staff, to deliver
  the desired outcome of cost savings. This was achieved by automating the accounts payable and
  accounts receivable processes with the introduction of new software and using the extra capacity to take
  on the additional treasury responsibilities. Conducting one-to-one meetings with accounts staff, I set new
  individual and team goals to re-energise and re-motivate the team, with an end result of 20% increased
  efficiency and a 40% reduction in costs. The process additionally improved relationships with suppliers,
  allowing more beneficial negotiations.
- Conducted a comprehensive and detailed business review in light of challenging economic circumstances and the need to adjust the business cost base. This involved significant research, deep analysis on each store, and modelling to highlight different short and long-term scenarios. During the process, I uncovered and addressed a number of inefficiencies, resulting in a 15% reduction in costs for most branches.

#### Financial Accountant, Agrocentro – PGG Wrightson, Uruguay

Aug 2014 - Jun 2017

I joined the company at a time of rapid development when financial controls and processes needed to be substantially upgraded to keep pace with and manage the growth of the business. Additionally, in 2015 I was heavily involved with the due diligence process for the acquisition of the company by PGG Wrightson.

#### **Responsibilities**

- Compile and prepare accurate and timely annual statutory accounts, ensuring all necessary compliances and meeting required deadlines.
- Prepare, review, and present monthly management accounts and reporting packs in line with group accounting policy and IAS requirements.
- Manage the payroll service, accounts payable and accounts receivable functions to provide an efficient and reliable finance framework to support business activities.
- Assist with the creation of the annual budget and forecasts and provide ongoing variance analysis and commentaries for robust assessment of business performance.
- Manage intercompany transactions, prepare cross-charges, reconciliation, netting and analysis.
- Assist with the coordination of year-end deliverables with external auditors to provide all necessary information for audit purposes.
- Assist with the due diligence process for the purchase of the business by PGG Wrightson, facilitating access to required information and producing reports needed by the purchaser's accounting team.

## VICTOR IRIPODI

#### **Achievements**

- During my early days with the company, I identified that the existing, highly manual monthly budgeting process was time-consuming, inefficient and prone to errors. I therefore initiated a new automated budgeting template which simplified the process for department managers. I created and delivered staff training on the new system and quickly realised a 20% reduction in errors and 30% increase in efficiency.
- My success in establishing an efficient and effective financial framework and deputising for the CFO, taking
  on and resolving issues in his absence, was recognised with promotion in 2017, when I was given greater
  responsibility including the management of a team of eight.

#### Assistant Accountant, Bado, Kuster, Zerbino & Rachetti, Uruguay

Jun 2013 - Jul 2014

Bado, Kuster, Zerbino & Rachetti is a leading legal and accountancy practice servicing a diverse range of clients across a number of industries. My role was to provide financial accounting services to a portfolio of customers using SAP.

#### Responsibilities

- Responsible for a portfolio of clients, building strong working relationships with client management and inhouse accountants to deliver valuable financial management support and advice.
- Manage the accounts payable and accounts receivable functions on behalf of clients, working with internal bookkeepers within the SAP system.
- Prepare, review, and lodge income tax returns and payroll tax reconciliations for clients.
- Maintain knowledge of the current tax regulatory framework, to ensure compliance and the correct application of appropriate adjustments, deductions, and credits to keep clients' taxes to a minimum.
- Assist with the external audit process, providing support to client staff and liaising with auditors on the necessary documentation.
- Create internal reports for clients to assist them with the financial management of the company.

#### Assistant Accountant, Bianchi & Associates, Uruguay

Apr 2011 - May 2013

Bianchi & Associates accounting firm provides professional services to the financial services industry in Uruguay with both local and international clients.

#### **Responsibilities**

- Act as an extension of clients' accounting teams and an external resource providing technical expertise and essential finance capabilities to support clients' businesses.
- Build productive relationships with client contacts and work collaboratively to facilitate the collection, processing and analysis of financial data for statutory and business management purposes.
- Gather the necessary information and prepare monthly financial statements to be presented to the Central Bank of Uruguay, in line with financial services regulatory requirements.
- Reconcile bank accounts, verify, code and enter invoices, and complete regular and ad hoc reports on behalf of the client.
- Deal with any discrepancies or queries, escalating complex issues to the partners for consideration, and provide advice to clients on the appropriate course of action.

#### **VOLUNTEER POSITIONS**

**2020** Red Cross – Shop Volunteer, Sydney

## VICTOR IRIPODI

•

### **EDUCATION**

**2021** Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

2021 CPA Program, Australia (in progress)

**2019** MBA, IEEM, Uruguay (associated to IESE)

2014 CPA, Universidad de la República, Uruguay

## **COMPUTER / TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- SAP
- Netsuite Oracle
- Advanced MS Excel (pivot tables, V lookups, macros)
- Oracle Hyperion
- SQL
- Tableu

#### **REFERENCES**

Available on request